Guide to the Morrison Institute for Population and Resource Studies Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Morrison Institute for Population and Resource Studies records
1970-1995
SC0865
Morrison Institute for Population and Resource Studies
7 Linear feet
These records, which are not comprehensive, include correspondence files, 1988-95; administrative files on fundraising, programs, and events, 1970-93; board minutes, 1988-91; and reports.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Morrison Institute for Population and Resource Studies, located at Stanford University, leads interdisciplinary study of population growth and its effects on social structures, national economies, resource availability, and the environment throughout the world. The three major facets to this endeavor -- research, education, and contribution to the formation of policy -- overlap in the major programs of the institute.
Description of the Collection
These records, which are not comprehensive, include correspondence files, 1988-95; administrative files on fundraising, programs, and events, 1970-93; board minutes, 1988-91; and reports.
Access Terms
Morrison Institute for Population and Resource Studies; Population research.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accesion ARCH-2005-281
  - Fred H. Bixby (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bixby Foundation (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Helen Coffey (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parrish, Will and Julie (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - M. W. Feldman (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Z. Feldman (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Leland Fikes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - W. E. Hall Co. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mitchell Energy and Development Corp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dean Morrison (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clyde and Martha Nichols (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ellis and Ann Stephens (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - UNFPA (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - UNDP (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Robert Wheeler (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Administrative Info, 1989-91 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Basic Proposal (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Decision Focus (Forest Management) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Genesis of Institute, 1970-93 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Prospectus 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Panel Discussion Feb. 2, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letters to the Institute, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Proposed activities, 1988-91 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Items for distribution (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Demography ½ Chair 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ecology-Economics Proposal 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Workshop, Economics and the Environment, 1991/92 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Workshop, Economics and the Environment, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Purpose of IPRS 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - CPS Evening at Faculty Club 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Public policy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Public talk (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Population studies fund raising 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Unlabelled [miscellaneous memos] 1988-89 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Forum, Environmental Science and Global Change, June 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Faculty workshop on deforestation (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Potential faculty (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - List of faculty affiliated with MIPRS (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - On the Environmental Carrying Capacity of the Earth (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cooperative Network (program plans) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Courses related to population and resource studies (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Materials for IPRS brochure (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stanberk [Stanford/Berkeley] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Memos sent (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Oren R. Lyons, Chief (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Jing Neng Li, "Structural and Spatial Economic Changes and Their Implications for Urbanization in Recent China," 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Madhav Gadgil, "India: an Intricate Mosaic of Varied Modes of Resource Use" 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Draft of progress report to Bergstroms, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Compton Foundation, proposal, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Morrison – gifts 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1988 February (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988 March (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988 April (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988 May (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1988 June (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1988 July (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1988 August (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988 September (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1988 October (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1988 November (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1988 December (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Denied student grants, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1989 January (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1989 February (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1989 March (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1989 April (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1989 May (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1989 June (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1989 July (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1989 August (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1989 September (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1989 October (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1989 November (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1989 December (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1989/90 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Anthony C. Bielenson, 1991-94 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to file 1991-95 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Population studies courses (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board meeting May 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Board meeting April 11, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Board meeting Nov. 22, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Board meeting June 2, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Board meeting April 27, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Board meeting Feb. 8, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Board meeting Feb. 8, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Board meeting Oct. 13, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Report to Board, Oct. 13, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Financial Report 1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Board meeting, May 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Miscellany 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Courses (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Prospectus and job description (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Marc 1-6-89 [re fundraising] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Reading (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Research reports (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Trusts – chairs – etc. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - MIPRS Board Oct. 13, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Budgets (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Research ideas (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - MIPRS publications (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Base Proposal corrections (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - New statement 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ecoperm / STEM – undergraduate course (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - News releases, June 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Funds Oct. 31, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Laura Fletcher (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Elaine Joyal (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: John Kerr (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Thomas Kiernan (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Linda Rainey (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Anthony Ibe Otuka (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Chuan-Kang Shih (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Louise Silberling (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Smita Singh (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - [student interested in IPRS]: Benard Amechi Ugbomeh (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - UCB graduate group in demography (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Princeton Visiting Scholars program (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - George Washington University (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - University of Washington (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Public Service Center (SU) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - World Wide Web (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Webster vs Reproductive Health Services (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - U.S. editors (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Seminars (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - H.R. – restrictions to family planning programs (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Ecological Sciences and Global Change 6/5/89 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Econet (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Blueprint for the Environment (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Demography of China (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - de Malvinsky, Jean (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Kennedy (Donald) bios (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Julian Simon (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Unlabelled [misc.] (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - MIPRS booklet/folder (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Unlabelled [sample of letterhead, etc.] (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Assorted publications (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Assorted publications, include the course reader "Population and Resources in a Changing World, Current Readings" 1989 (Box 7)
  - Files and publications from Collaborative Research Program in Ecol. & Env. Assessment for Eastern Europe and Eurasia [in Russian] (Box 8)
  - Restricted Files:
    - Africa, India & Israel exchanges; grant authorizations; Fellowship information; potential post-docs; and administrative files (Box 9)
    - Grant authorizations for individuals 1989-95; recommendations for graduate awards; progress reports on research; generic files on student awards 1984-86 (Box 10)